[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 13
I WANT A BACK-AND-FORTH RALLY
- [Yukiko] How are you feeling?
- [Chinatsu] Feeling good.
[Yukiko] You won't be back
till next week, right?
[Chinatsu] As long as we're winning.
Do your best! But don't get hurt.
[Chinatsu] Thanks.
I'm heading out.
CHINATSU
NATIONALS
[door opens, closes]
[Chinatsu sighs]
Wow. The stars are still out.
- [footsteps approaching]
- [Taiki] Chinatsu!
Uh, Taiki.
- You forgot something.
- Huh?
- Oh, thanks so much.
- No sweat.
[pleasant music playing]
[Taiki] I should
say something, shouldn't I?
I feel like "Do your best"
doesn't really capture it.
But saying, "The people you're playing
are high schoolers just like you,"
is also pretty weak.
Chinatsu, your wish bracelet
hasn't come off yet.
It's strange, right?
Because the wish I had made
was to make it to nationals this year.
[Taiki exclaims]
Let's add on another wish then!
Add one?
It hasn't come off, so I think we can.
I wish that Chinatsu doesn't get injured,
can play at the top of her game
after all her hard work,
and emerge victorious,
that will be the new wish. [grunts]
Maybe that's one wish too many?
Your wish to go to nationals
came true without the bracelet,
so this shouldn't be a big deal.
[grunts]
Sending positive energy!
Mm. I don't actually feel anything.
What?
- Let's try directly.
- [gasps softly]
- You've got this!
- Yeah.
And if you need more,
I'll send it from here!
Uh...
You know, I gotta say...
you are quite the flirt, Taiki.
- Huh?
- I better go.
I'll see you later.
[Taiki] It's kinda rude
to think this, but...
you're one to talk!
If you want my honest opinion,
I think both of you are.
Her asking me for a high five
is way more flirty!
What you're doing
is also pretty flirtatious.
And that reminds me...
I'm not sure if this is related
to what Chinatsu said to you,
but that girl, Imada,
from the girls' basketball team,
she knows that you and Hina
went to the fireworks festival,
just the two of you.
- So Chinatsu probably knows about it.
- What?!
I mean, they went together,
so she's gotta know about it.
[exclaims] You... you think so?
But wait. Hold on a sec.
Yeah, with some friends.
Does she think that I lied to her?
So, as far as Chinatsu knows,
I'm just some guy who lies
so he can go somewhere alone with a girl.
And, I mean, Hina and I did
go alone together after all, but...
[amusing music playing]
[Kyo] And he's frozen.
Anyway, practice time.
Wow. You came outta that
faster than I thought.
Aren't you a bit worried that
she may think you two were on a date?
Well, there's nothing
I can do about it now.
I'll apologize for it turning into a lie.
But I have something more important to do.
Chinatsu certainly doesn't have time
for this either.
She's not sweating it.
That doesn't make me feel better.
Oop, excuse me.
And then we do this, then this way...
Looks like Hina's locked in.
It is nationals after all.
And there's someone else
who's stressed out.
Hey. Don't you think it's unfair?
The venue for nationals this year.
Basketball is in Kyushu,
volleyball in Tohoku,
rhythmic gymnastics is in Kansai.
Badminton's in the prefecture
next to ours.
[grunts, pants]
But look at it this way, now there's
the rest of us that can cheer you on.
That isn't the point I'm making,
all right?
[Nishida] My bad.
I wanted to eat local foods
and bathe in hot springs!
[boy] Haryu's in a bad mood,
but he does love to travel.
No, anybody would be that tense
before nationals.
I'm just pretty impressed
at how calm he is while playing.
Which one of you is going to play me next?
[boys exclaim]
I can play!
I won't go easy.
Right! [stutters] Yes!
NATIONAL HIGH SCHOOL
BADMINTON TOURNAMENT
[Taiki] This place is jam-packed.
People who survived the tournaments
are here from all over Japan.
That's Yusa from Sajikawa.
[Hyodo] There are two slots
for nationals next year.
My money's on Haryu and Yusa to go.
[Taiki grunts softly]
- [Karen] Taiki Inomata?
- [grunts softly]
Wait, Karen?
[Taiki] Oh, right.
She's here to cheer on Haryu.
Your timing couldn't be better!
Chii's game is today,
so I've been talking to her on the phone!
- Say hello?
- [exclaims softly]
[Taiki] I really would like
to talk to her.
It's Taiki.
[line disconnects]
Sorry, did she already hang up?
[Taiki] Karen did this on purpose!
Definitely something
Haryu's girlfriend would do.
Sorry about that.
You probably wanted
to talk to the girl you like.
It's fine.
What?!
How did you know I like her?
I can tell based
on how you reacted just now.
How long have you liked her?
Before she moved in? Or was it after that?
You even know about us living together?
Chinatsu did share
that part with me herself.
It's gotta be tough
living with a girl you have a crush on.
Well, it's not so bad.
[Taiki] I get it.
She can tell Karen all the things
that might be hard
to tell her friends at school.
So how's it going?
Is she handling things okay?
She's almost too polite and accommodating.
Plus, she cleans everything that she uses,
and she always tries to help us
with all the chores around the house.
[Karen] Does she still stare off
into space sometimes?
[Taiki] She definitely does.
[Karen] But then,
whenever I'm eating snacks,
she ends up staring right at me.
[Taiki] Staring is how
she asks for things.
It feels like time goes by slower
whenever I hang out with Chinatsu.
Can't say that I mind.
[pleasant music playing]
[Karen] He does seem like the kind of guy
she'd be okay living with.
I wasn't expecting you.
[Karen] I was expecting a thank you.
I know that you're super busy.
[Karen] Yeah, and I made time for this.
- It'll help, right?
- Gosh, she's stunning.
- Your pretty girlfriend cheering you on?
- She's gorgeous.
- [Haryu] Don't say that about yourself.
- Is your opponent good?
I think the same level.
- And you warmed up?
- 'Bout to.
Make sure that you win this one.
Yeah, I know.
[Karen] This way?
- [Taiki] Right. It's court five.
- [phone vibrates]
Wait, hang on.
I need to respond
to this real quick, it's work.
All done.
You and Haryu...
You're an amazing couple.
You balance your lives,
when you're alone and together.
[exclaims softly]
Is it challenging for you
to find the balance
between practice and dating Chii?
No, I wasn't trying
to make this about myself!
I wouldn't say we're amazing.
There was a lot of uncertainty
for both of us in the beginning.
We definitely wondered
if we were taking on too much.
I've been friends with Kengo
since we were in fifth grade.
I started to have feelings for him
in junior high.
But I thought that both of us
might have other things to focus on.
And I had a suspicion
that he might've felt the same way.
Although, every once in a while,
we'd hang out, just the two of us,
or talk on the phone.
And it started getting to me,
like, "What is this between us?"
[chuckles]
But then, one day,
the nature of their relationship
had unexpectedly changed.
[Taiki] Why'd she switch to third person?
[Karen] I was feeling bummed out
after a bad day at work,
and had been venting to Kengo
about it on the phone.
And a few minutes after we hung up,
I got a text from him.
[phone vibrates]
KENGO HARYU
CAN YOU COME OUT?
- [Karen] Kengo!
- [grunts softly]
What are you doing here?
I was on a run anyway,
and wanted to give you this.
What is it?
It's my diary from second grade.
I've never shared it.
Wait, your diary?
TODAY, I SMASHED ICE WITH MY HEAD
[Haryu] It's honestly
a good read, totally stupid.
Read it before bed,
and feel better knowing
that there's someone
this dumb in the world.
I know you pretty well.
You'll keep overthinking,
and not be able to sleep.
We'll figure this out.
Why don't we both talk in the morning?
[romantic music playing]
[chuckles] You're such an idiot.
Yeah, I know.
This one part's really good--
[gasps]
Now that you've done this for me,
I can't help but think about you.
- And then I told him how I felt.
- [breathing heavily]
I couldn't ignore my feelings, you know.
[Taiki] She's at an Olympic level, too.
A gold medalist.
- [Karen] We talked about it after that.
- I'm all set.
[Karen] And Kengo was hesitant at first.
But we decided to go for it,
with the understanding that we'd break up
if either of us
let work or practice slide.
Since we knew
we had feelings for each other,
we couldn't go back to how things were.
I didn't wanna decide
based on a worst-case scenario,
especially without giving it a shot.
When you think about it, we're still
in the middle of a trial run, you know.
Go for it!
Keep it up!
[Taiki] I guess I had made the assumption
that they were both
just good at everything.
EIMEI
WAKABAYASHI HIGH
- That's it, you got this!
- [all cheering indistinctly]
[referee] First game, winner...
- Yes, Haryu. That's it.
- [all cheering]
Nice one!
[Taiki] I have absolutely no idea
what Chinatsu is thinking.
And I haven't told her
what's on my mind either.
[Hyodo] Good for you, Haryu.
Making it this far.
Well, I have to hang in there
until our match.
Too bad we'll see each other
in the third round instead of finals.
Speaking of which,
I hear that you had an interesting chat
with one of our first-years.
About the two players
who will be here next year.
If it were me and Taiki, would you be mad?
The venue next year
will be different, though.
[Haryu] Went right over his head.
Nah, I wouldn't be mad at all
if it was the two of you.
It's whoever wins prefecturals.
Although,
if you can't take me
in at least one game today, Haryu,
you might not be here next year.
What are you talking about?
I came here to beat you today.
[announcer on PA] Your attention.
Hyodo of Sajikawa High School,
and Haryu of Eimei High School,
please make your way to court nine.
[grunts]
[inaudible]
[tense music playing]
[pants]
[Hyodo] That's what
I'm talking about, Haryu.
If only you had been
more aggressive right of the bat,
you could've scored a point.
You're being too cautious
and too defensive.
That's why you keep giving up
so many points.
You can't shake the image of losing to me.
He already lost the first game.
But he still has
a chance of winning, right?
Yeah, we play to 21 points.
Two games is a win.
[Haryu] Dammit,
I've fallen into Hyodo's rhythm.
It's like a replay of prefecturals.
She's looking pretty worried.
It's rare to see her like that.
GRADE 5 CLASS 2 SCHEDULE
[Haryu] Karen and I first met
when we were in fifth grade.
- Haryu!
- Can you help us with math after school?
Sorry, I have swim lessons Wednesdays.
[Haryu] My parents encouraged me
to try a lot of things.
Piano, Monday, swimming, Wednesday,
cram school, Saturday.
Even calligraphy at one point.
Somehow we found time,
and my dad took me
to a badminton club one day,
just for fun, and I really got into it.
That's its own story though.
SWIMMING SCHOOL
I was pretty good at most things.
I thought that in itself was my strength.
And then I met Karen.
We have a new friend joining us today.
This is Karen Moriya.
It's very nice to meet you.
- She's cute.
- She looks grown-up!
She's pretty. Look how long her legs are!
- [coach] Can you give us a swim?
- [Karen] Sure!
[Haryu] If you asked anyone,
they'd say she was beautiful,
and that everyone would fall for...
Well, you'd be wrong
about the second part.
[coach] Moriya! Use your legs!
No, those are your hands!
[bubbling, gasping]
- Yum, oxygen!
- [Haryu] Hey.
Huh?
Why'd you bother coming to a school
known for its swimming program?
What?
Doing something
that you're not any good at
is just gonna set you up
to completely embarrass yourself.
[groans softly]
[Haryu gasps]
[gasps] What are you doing?
- So then you teach me!
- [exclaims]
You feel bad I looked dumb
in front of everyone.
So why don't you show me a thing or two?
I came to this school to learn after all.
Uh... I didn't mean it like that.
[Karen] I can't stand
not being able to swim.
'Cause my dream
is to swim with the dolphins.
[Haryu] That's why you're here?
[Karen] Yeah, and it's not fair to decide
that I'm bad at something
without giving myself
a fair shot to learn.
Just because I'm struggling right now,
doesn't mean that I will
still be struggling with it in the future.
[exclaims softly]
[Haryu] By the time she left our school,
she was able to swim
the 50-meter freestyle.
Even our coach was moved.
After that, we went to different schools,
but we lived close to each other.
So we started to hang out together.
- 'Sup?
- What are you doing here?
You said you won
your badminton tournament, so I thought...
I'd let you have dinner with me.
[Haryu] We kept in touch about our lives,
and supported each other.
In spite of wanting
to take our relationship further,
I kept making excuses,
thinking I shouldn't get in her way.
That's why...
Oh, Kengo.
I like you a lot.
[Haryu] ...my heart ached.
Here was Karen,
the scent of shampoo lingering,
her eyes looking shyly down.
My heart ached, both,
from my feelings for her,
and from the shame of not being the one
to confess my own feelings first.
[uplifting music playing]
She's always been the cool one.
Just like she took on swimming,
she always chose to challenge herself,
despite the fear and embarrassment
that might come along with it.
That's the girlfriend watching me.
If I don't find the cool side
of myself now, then when will I?
- [Taiki] He's catching up!
- [pants]
You got this!
[grunts]
[Taiki] Haryu, keep it up!
- Good footwork! Come on, take him down!
- [grunts]
[all exclaiming]
[pants]
[Taiki] He's got a game on the board!
[Haryu grunts] I can win.
There's still a chance.
[grunts]
I can't give up.
My temperature's rising.
[grunts]
My feet are still with me.
- [Taiki] Go, Haryu!
- [Haryu] I can hear them cheering me on.
I'm still in good shape.
My mind is calm.
[grunts]
Yet somehow,
this three-point gap won't last forever.
Narrow your focus.
Watch your opponent.
You won a game already.
Your abilities are just as strong as his.
Keep your feet moving. React fast.
Then you'll make it to the shuttle.
You'll make it.
[music fades]
[shuttlecock thuds]
[referee] Match winner:
Hyodo of Sajikawa High School.
[breathing shakily]
- [all cheering]
- [Haryu] Damn it.
I can't believe his smash
was still that powerful.
I can't compete with that.
It's been fun going up against you...
these two years.
[Haryu] Thank you... for everything.
[moody music playing]
Even from a player's perspective,
badminton matches end in a second.
For real. They're over before you know it.
I'm going on a quick run!
Exercise after all that?
That's what I said.
Watch this for me, would you?
It's been said 1,000 times before,
but seeing someone
work as hard as he does,
makes you wanna do the same.
[soft music playing]
It really does.
- I'm crossing my fingers for you, too.
- Thanks.
For sports and romance!
[exclaims]
Will you tell her how you feel?
You're already living together,
which is more than most couples get to do.
It's because we live together
that I'm hesitant.
- What?
- If she rejects me...
I worry that she won't feel comfortable
at my house anymore.
Living with us, Chinatsu is already
so polite and sensitive.
Uh. Wait, but you have
a crush on Chii, right?
Right.
And, like, you want to be
in a relationship with her, right?
Uh. [stutters] Yes.
Then, isn't it a lot creepier
if she's living with someone
who secretly has feelings for her?
What?!
[groans]
I hadn't thought of it like that.
Karen's right.
It might be creepy
if she has to live with a guy
who's constantly watching her,
and sniffs the air
whenever she walks past.
[sighs]
C'mon, don't start overthinking it.
Taiki, it can be nice to consider
how the other person might be feeling,
but at the end of the day, you can't know
what Chii's actually thinking.
Sometimes it's important
that there are moments
you choose not to think too.
The way things are going,
you're gonna be rallying
against a wall your whole life.
[grunts softly]
Is that what you want?
[Taiki] No, I want a back-and-forth rally.
[Karen] Okay. Then go for it.
[pants]
[Karen] Welcome back.
What? You're leaving?
- Yeah, I've got a train to catch.
- Thanks so much for coming to this.
Oh, yeah, it was fun,
even beyond the match.
[soft piano music playing]
Kengo, this might be
a tough question to answer, but...
For a second-year, is it hard
to get any better than you are right now?
I mean, yeah, I'd say so.
Almost everyone else
was a third-year, so there's that.
- I gotcha.
- Hm?
[sighs softly]
Okay, then. I should get going.
- Karen.
- [exclaims]
Next time, I'll win more matches.
Yeah.
Ew, you're smelly.
Uh, hey!
All right. Go study up
on the other matches now.
Yup. Get home safe.
If what you said to me was a lie,
I'm cutting down on our date nights.
Yeah, I gotcha.
That's more of a punishment for you
than it is for me.
Hey, which court
is Hoshino High School playing on?
It's court 11.
Come with me, Taiki.
Yeah!
[Taiki] Wait. He smells good.
[closing theme song playing]